# **Pavlos Karalis**

I'm a Full-Stack Developer capable of tackling a project from multiple-perspectives, and can dependably deliver tailored, maintainable results via a crafted approach. Furthermore, with 7 years of prior experience as a DC metro area event photographer, resourcefulness, professionalism, and ingenuity have all become second nature.

Rockville, Maryland
(301) 642-5129
pavloskaralis@gmail.com
Portfolio | LinkedIn | GitHub

## **DEVELOPER EXPERIENCE | DEVELOPER PORTFOLIO**

## **Software Engineering Fellow** — *General Assembly*

2019 - 2020

700 Hour course on Full-Stack Development, Frameworks, and APIs.

Traveler: Full-Stack trip planner with shared user model Project
React, Redux-Thunk, Rails, PostgreSQL, Bcrypt README.md

Go-Fish: 2 to 4 player DOM game against programmed AI Project

jQuery, Vanilla JavaScript, Photoshop

README.md

Appstractor: Full-stack image filter application/gallery Project
Express, Mongoose, EJS, jQuery, Unsplash API README.md

Foodie: Full-Stack list editor with shared user model

React, Express, Mongoose, Passport, Trello

README.md

## **Frontend**

React

Redux-Thunk Styled Components

HTML5 CSS3

Javascript ES6

Axios SCSS jQuery Bootstrap Chart.js

#### **OTHER EXPERIENCE**

## **Real Estate Photographer** — *Redfin*

2018 - PRESENT

- Capturing residential properties for Redfin's Maryland region.
- Onboarding and mentoring new photographer employees.

## **Freelance Photographer** — Pavlos Karalis Photography

2012 - 2019

- Captured headshots, events, and weddings for various clientele.
- Hired and managed assistant photographers and videographers.

## **Event Photographer** — *EPNAC*

2015 - 2018

- Captured corporate/government events with prominent speakers.
- Oversaw team travel assignments in cities across the country.

### **EDUCATION**

Corcoran College of Art and Design — BFA Photography

#### **Backend**

Node.js
Express
Ruby
Rails
MongoDB
PostgreSQL
Passport.js
Bcrypt
EJS
JSX
MVC

Restful Routes

#### Other

Search + Sort Algorithms
Data Structures
Github
Adobe Photoshop
Adobe Premiere Pro
Avid Pro Tools